childmind.org 2013-05-08

# Privacy | Child Mind Institute

We at the Child Mind Institute, Inc. ("CMI"), want this site to be a safe and private place for users. We will do our part by not requiring you to register or provide any information at all to use most sections and features of this Web site. In turn, you can do your part by reading this policy and taking the steps outlined below.

There are certain actions and areas of the site that will require you to provide personal information. These include:

•               becoming a member of our network

•               signing up for email or newsletters

•               commenting

•               sending an e-mail question

•               making a donation

•               applying for a part-time, full-time, or volunteer position

•               accessing the patient portal

Any time you provide personal information, this privacy policy will govern our use of the information you have provided.

**By submitting personal information to us, you agree that we may use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.** We will update this privacy policy as we deem necessary. You should be sure to reread this policy in its entirety from time to time.

**Personal Information You Choose to Provide**

In order to gain access to certain areas of our site or to use certain features, you may choose to provide personal information. **If you do submit information to us, we will use that information for the purposes for which it was submitted. We may also use your information in other ways, such as to contact you about other CMI-related activities and/or fundraising campaigns or as otherwise disclosed to you at the point of collection, and we may share your information with other like-minded organizations, including other CMI entities, for similar purposes.**

**For example:**

If you make an online donation to us, your information will be added to one or more of our supporter lists and databases and you will be contacted about other CMI activities, news, and/or fundraising campaigns.

If you join or opt in to our e-mail list, you will receive informational updates and action alerts about child and adolescent mental health-related issues. Our list is electronic, and therefore we need an e-mail address to contact you. We also need your full postal address in order for our systems to match you to the correct state and federal districts, thereby ensuring that you are primarily sending messages to your designated elected officials.

If you use our Web site to submit your resume or materials for a paid or volunteer position, your information will be stored in a centralized database and may be accessible to other CMI entities, including our separately incorporated affiliates, which may be seeking candidates for full-time, part-time, or volunteer positions.

**We also may provide opportunities for you to submit additional personal information,** such as Web site feedback. By submitting this information to us, you give us permission to receive it, review it, edit it, store it, post it on our Web site, and use it in appropriate settings. To protect your privacy, please do not include any identifying information in your submissions.

You should be aware that we use third-party vendors to provide services on this site and in our off-line business operations. The information that you submit on this site may be provided to those vendors on a confidential basis so that those vendors can provide services (such as maintaining our databases, sending e-mail messages to activists or supporters, facilitating our fundraising activities and campaigns, or processing credit card transactions) on our behalf.

**Other than as described in this privacy policy, or as may be necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of our organization, our clients, or others, or as may be necessary to comply with applicable law, we will not give or sell the personal information you provide online. We also reserve the right to share personal information you provide with legal authorities if it is, in our sole opinion, necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected fraud or situations involving threats or potential harm, or if required by law (such as by a subpoena, court order, or other legal means).**

**Financial Information You Choose to Provide**

If you choose to make an online donation, you will have to provide your credit card billing information. As this information is collected and transferred over the Internet to our secure server, it is encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, the industry-standard security technology that is designed to protect sensitive information. If you are making a donation, the credit card information that you provide at the time of donation is used only to process your donation and will not be used for any other purposes.

**Information Automatically Collected and Stored**

As is true of most Web sites, we automatically collect and store some information about your computer and your visit and store it in log files. This information includes information such as your computer's (or your ISP's) Internet Protocol (IP) address (this is not your e-mail address); the domain from which you access the Internet (e.g., "verizon.net" or "Stanford.edu"); the name, version, and specifications of your computer and your computer's operating system; the URL of the Web site, if any, from which you came to our site; the date and time you arrived at our site and how long you spent on the site; and which pages you visited.

We use this information to formulate statistics (possibly with the help of outside experts) that show the number of visitors to the different sections of our site and to help us make our site more useful to visitors. For example, we use the browser information to help us design our Web site so that as many people as possible will be able to view the pages correctly. These statistics do not reveal personal information.

**E-mail a Friend**

If you use our E-mail a Friend service to tell a friend about our site or newsletter, we will ask you for your name, your e-mail address and your friend's e-mail address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the site using your name and e-mail address as the "from" e-mail address. CMI does not use your name, your e-mail address or your friend's e-mail information for any other purpose. We will use the information you provide only to send the e-mail you request.

**Public Forums**

The CMI Web site features several community areas and other public forums where users with similar interests or medical conditions can share information and support one another or where users can post questions for experts to answer. We also offer online discussions moderated by medical or healthcare experts. Our communities are open to the public and should not be considered private.

**Any information you share in any online community area (including Personally Identifiable and Personal Health Information) is by design open to the public and is not private. You should think carefully before posting any Personally Identifiable or Personal Health Information in any public forum. What you post can be seen, disclosed to, or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we cannot control or predict, including to contact you for unauthorized purposes. As with any public forum on any site, the information you post may also show up in third-party search engines such as Google, Yahoo, MSN, Bing, etc.**

**Web site Registration and Interactive Tools**

After you have registered as a member of the CMI Web site, you may choose to use certain interactive content, tools, and services that may ask you to voluntarily provide other types of information, including Personal Health Information.

**Special Information for Children under 13 and Their Parents**

The Child Mind Institute is committed to providing a safe and secure online experience for children who visit our site. We are dedicated to safeguarding any personal information collected online and to helping parents and children have positive experiences on the Internet. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without prior verifiable parental consent. If you are under 13 and would like to participate in the message forums or other areas of the site that require your information, please have your parent or guardian send an e-mail with a verifiable identity, giving us permission to allow you to register. If we have not received parental permission for a user who states to be or is found to be under 13, we cannot, by law, respond to questions or publish any content from that user.

Parents can revoke their consent and ask that information about their children be deleted from the site, by contacting us via e-mail. To do this or to review personal information collected from children, we must verify the identity of the requesting parent. When a parent revokes consent, we will stop collecting, using, or disclosing information from that child. To respect the privacy of parents, information collected and used for the sole purpose of obtaining verifiable parental consent or providing notice is not maintained in retrievable form by the site if parental consent is not obtained after a reasonable time.

**Use of Cookies**

Cookies are small text files that are placed either on your computer's hard drive ("persistent cookies") or in your computer's random-access memory ("session cookies"). We use both persistent cookies and session cookies for various sections of our Web site.

Session Cookies: We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate certain sections of our Web site. If you choose to provide personal information by using an interactive application on our site, such as by joining our e-mail list, making an online donation, or asking a question, we place a session cookie on your computer so that you will be recognized as you move around our Web pages. Unless you opt in to change these session cookies to persistent cookies (see "Persistent Cookies" below), the information is used for only the duration of your browser session. For example, if you join our activist network and then navigate different pages of our Web site, the cookie will maintain the information you entered when you filled out the activist registration page. As you move through the site, any fields requiring information about you that has already been captured will be prepopulated. However, once you close your browser window, the session cookie times out. If you open a new browser window and return to our Web site, your personal information fields will not be prepopulated.

Persistent Cookies: We use persistent cookies in some sections of our Web site to provide greater accuracy in our analysis of the information that is automatically collected about your visit to our site. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. These cookies do not collect personal information. We do not link the information collected through these cookies with other personal data that you provide to us.

In certain circumstances, you may be given the option to turn a session cookie into a persistent cookie on your computer (e.g., "Would you like us to remember your password?" messages). If you opt to turn a session cookie into a persistent cookie, that persistent cookie will remember your personal information (e.g., user name and password) and will not time out at the end of your browser session. See "Your Help Is Needed" for more information.

Disabling Cookies: Persistent cookies leave a record on your computer that you have visited our site. However, you have the ability to remove cookies from your computer. Your Internet browser's "Help" section will give you information on how to delete cookies. In addition, there are many Web sites that provide browser- and operating system-specific information on how to delete cookies. When thinking about whether you want to delete cookies, you should be aware that some sites require cookies to function properly. If you delete cookies, you may have to reregister with some sites or you may notice difficulty in browsing some sites after you delete cookies.

**Google Analytics**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States . Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

**Security**

**Information submitted via the Internet, including through a Web page or e-mail, is subject to interception or incorrect routing, and the Internet is not a fully secure communications channel. Please consider this prior to submitting any information to us via this Web site.**

Certain sections of this site have heightened security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information you have provided. The security measures used on this site include, but are not limited to, industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology, firewalls, and internal policies to maintain the security of stored data. While we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

When you register with or donate to us, or become a member of our supporter community through this Web site, you will have a personal subscription management page, where you will be able to edit your personal information as well as review your messaging, advocacy, and/or donation records. Access to your personal subscription management page is controlled to protect the privacy of your data — our Web site requires that you log on with your e-mail address and personal password to access your personal subscription management page. The log-on process may be automated if you choose to accept the placement of a persistent cookie on your PC. See "Use of Cookies" and "Your Help Is Needed" for more information on persistent cookies.

Remember, breaches of security also can occur when users are not vigilant in protecting their own information. The next section of our privacy policy suggests some actions you can take to help control the security of your personal information.

**Your Help Is Needed**

Although we do our best to protect your privacy on our site, we need your help.

You have control over your own privacy. Think carefully before providing any personal or financial information online.

Although this site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information you have provided, no e-mail or Web transmission is completely secure against interception. If you are worried because your communication is very sensitive, do not send it electronically.

Remember that we cannot protect your privacy once you leave our site, such as by "hyperlink." So when you visit other Web sites, check each one's privacy policy yourself and be careful about the information you submit or share.

You should be aware that in some areas of this site we utilize personalization measures designed to make your site experience more enjoyable (i.e., personalized links in e-mail that allow data fields to be prepopulated with certain personal information). We need your help to protect the information embedded in these links. You should always keep your e-mail account information secure and not allow others to access your e-mail account.

In addition, you should forward our e-mail messages or other Web site information (such as volunteer or job postings) to others only through the buttons or links provided within the e-mail or Web site. When you use your e-mail system's forwarding capabilities, others may be able to take actions in your name and/or access your personal information.

You may be given the option to turn on a persistent cookie on your computer (see "Use of Cookies" above). Remember that once you have set a persistent cookie that is linked to your personal information, anyone can access your personal information by using your computer.

In addition to the records left on your computer by cookies, your browser and operating system contain other records of your Web browsing and other actions (e.g., browser history). As with cookies, in your browser's "Help" section or through other Web sites that provide detailed information for each browser and operating system, you can find information about how to clear these history trails. See "Use of Cookies — Disabling Cookies" above.

**How to Unsubscribe or Contact Us about Your Information**

If you do not want to receive any e-mail from us in the future, visit your personal subscription management page to deactivate your account. Note that your records will remain in CMI's databases, but your log-in and e-mail address will be deactivated.

If you wish to review the contact information we have on file for you, correct your contact information or provide a change of address, or inform us how you wish your contact information to be used, please contact our staff (see below).

You may contact us by mail, e-mail, or telephone, as follows:

Mail: Child Mind Institute, 445 Park Avenue, New York, NY 10022

Policy Last Updated: September 30, 2010

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes here, so that you are continually aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify our privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently.

© 2010 Child Mind Institute. All rights reserved. "CMI" and its logo are registered service marks of the Child Mind Institute, Inc.
